That was way too much losing lately.
We shall only win today.
No losses are acceptable today.
I will do everything I can to win.
Can you feel that tingle in your balls?
That's right.
That is the sign we are going to win.
Not testicular cancer, don't worry about it.
Ahhh yeah.
God it feels good.
Something about today is special.
Can you feel it?
Because I sure can.
Stop!
It's time for Isaac.
Oh yeah.
Guys, I am disappointed in myself because I lost so much lately.
I will say though, I dominated those challenges.
Just saying.
But you know, when it comes to the real game.
The streaking.
I failed myself.
Not today.
Hey, we got a win streak of one.
I forgot we won the last time we did this.
Hey, there we go.
Not bad.
I actually thought we were at minus one or something.
The goal today, no matter what, is to get to win streak three.
That is my dream.
And you know what?
I think I'm going to pick the characters I want to play.
I want to play Apollyon.
One of them for sure.
Looks like he has wings.
I think I want to play Eden.
Look at the page.
Oh, that says it's like bloody and shit.
There's like blood all over.
Like what the fuck?
Wait, Samson has a brimstone thing.
I can't not think of a penis when I see that symbol.
I'm sorry, but it's the first thing that comes to mind.
He has a penis.
This guy.
Wait, I've done more on this guy than I have on Isaac.
Okay, we're going to play Isaac as well.
So Isaac, Apollyon, and... I do love Samson, actually.
But what about Cain?
We could do some cheers.
I may or may not have gotten myself a little bit of coke.
The drink, don't worry.
It's the sugar-free version.
It's okay, I'm allowed.
Okay, okay, here we go, here we go.
We got the d6, baby.
No mistakes allowed.
I am locked in today, dude.
I am going to use everything I can to my advantage to win.
There will be no cutting corners today.
Every poop will be destroyed.
A small rock has appeared.
What?
Whoa!
What the?
All right, that's a great start.
Not sure why that happened, but I like it.
They're going to jump towards me or what?
Okay, that's fine.
Hey, you.
There's one more.
There you are.
You know what?
Let's try and destroy him near the wall down here.
Okay, so no secret.
Not bad, huh?
Keep moving.
So the guy in the top left, we don't want to aggro him yet.
Oh, no, we got hit.
Massive blunder there.
Okay, the first blunder.
The second blunder is now out of the way.
That means it's allowed to keep playing normally.
I don't know what I'm saying.
Obviously, we're going to eat the pills.
Okay, it went so well, and then it all of a sudden went so not well.
That's just the nature of things.
What the hell is that?
Wait a minute here.
That's new.
I got to take it.
Nod leaf.
It's unbreakable.
Do I have a... Wait, what?
Standing still for one second will turn Isaac into stone and grant invincibility.
Taking any action breaks the... Whoa!
That's cool!
So I can go into a corner and cry, and stay there forever?
Is that right?
And then just stand like this.
What if, check this out, we get some sort of creep.
We go in a corner, we put the creep down, and we turn to stone.
We just stand there.
How is that not a winning strategy?
Huh?
That sounds like a great idea.
Compost.
Pay to play.
Doors and objects that normally require keys to open require coins instead.
That could be good, depending on how many coins we find.
Oh my god, that was almost a catastrophe.
It's okay.
I need to focus.
This guy's gonna jump at me?
Yep.
All good.
Boss has been found.
Let me think here.
I'm not going towards boss yet.
I'm kind of sad that the stone transformation isn't Jim.
You know?
That would be fun.
If it ain't Jim, then I'm not him.
That doesn't even make sense.
Do I use my last blue heart on this to get in here?
No, but I think I'm gonna use one bomb here.
Actually, no, no, we're gonna play so safe.
I'm gonna check this wall.
Okay, there's nothing blocking it.
What about from here?
No, so this is pretty much guaranteed.
Haha!
Not bad!
Four coins?
I mean, it's a start.
I think I will actually go into that curse room.
Yeah, we got a little bit of extra HP that we normally wouldn't have had, right?
Get him out of here.
Money!
Oh, it wasn't really money.
It was the potential for money.
That's fine.
Okay, so we got a heart in here.
We're gonna grab that.
Four coins?
That's not gonna... or it's not gonna do much for us in the shop.
Could get a key, I guess.
Ah, I don't really want those items.
It's time for a pin.
We're totally gonna D6.
What's coming out of him, you know?
It's gonna take a while to kill this guy.
Okay, going pretty well.
No problem.
Ah, that's actually a good item, man.
I think I'm gonna take it.
Like, plus one lock, plus one health.
Yeah, I'm not gonna change that.
That's good.
I'm happy.
Floor two.
Recursion has been activated.
Curse of the Unknown.
So we don't know how much HP we have, except we do.
We have four.
Four HP right now.
We're gonna keep track of it.
Maybe do some stepping, depending on how many red hearts we find.
Going buckets at me.
So rude, actually.
Nice.
No problem.
We take all the poop in case we find something.
I'm actually gonna go to the right first.
It feels more correct.
Oh man, he had a predictive throw there.
Like, he saw where I was walking and he threw... Oh man, he's actually destroying my boobs.
The ones I need.
Also, what did this penny do for me again?
50% chance to gain one additional cent each time you pick up a coin.
Okay.
Wait, what's the difference between a cent and a coin?
Monstro's tooth.
No, that's an active.
We don't want to use that.
Uh, I could use my D6 here.
I think it's worth it.
It's definitely worth it.
Ah, but man, I want to keep my D6.
Oh, that's a tough one.
I think I'm going to keep my D6 for this floor and then switch back to the Bible before I leave.
This is the plan.
I just want to get more charges on this so I can re-roll a potential devil item.
But we did unfortunately lose some devil chance because we took damage.
Kind of hard not to take damage here in this place.
Bro, can you please die?
Man, those flies are annoying.
Okay.
So far, so good.
I want to find a creep generator.
Hey, Jackie, what's up?
Jackie is at my feet.
Don't even think about jumping up, Jackie.
I have no keys.
Oh, I didn't even see those guys, man.
They were invisible.
Jackie is actually distracting me right now.
Jackie, stop.
While I'm doing this, it's very important to be successful in Isaac.
You know this.
Man, they're just bouncing around.
I think we have three hearts right now.
Oh, I thought it was going to fart on me there.
So far, so good.
Three buttons.
Oh, Jim.
Oh, it's getting worse and worse.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my goodness.
Guys, it's not going well.
This floor is fucking me right now.
I may as well go in here, I guess, and beat the bejesus out of this boss, but I think I'm at like one heart if I had to guess.
Oh, not this again.
Please, please, please, please, please, please.
Gimme.
I like that more.
This is damage, right?
The booger.
Yes.
Good.
Okay, well, the being rich dreams are over.
That's fine.
Wish me luck against little blub.
I need it.
Boogers.
Just keep applying the boogers to the boss so we can have some dots, you know?
Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow.
I'm scared.
Dude, am I dead?
I must be at like half a heart.
I must be.
We have to take this just for the survival.
Don't want to reroll that.
Ten coins, though.
Would love to go to the shop and buy something, but I don't have a key.
Let's try and see if we can find a treasure room.
So I have a theory that there's one right here.
Let's check every corner.
There's nothing on this wall.
What about back here?
Jackie, please.
Okay, look at this.
There's nothing there, then.
Confirmed.
Could be down.
It could be in here.
Okay, it's not in there.
Damn.
Let me see here.
Could maybe be over here.
The thing is, though, I don't even know if these rules I have made up for myself are even like valid.
Oh, fuck.
I don't know.
I give up.
I can't use all my bombs.
I'm saving them.
No key for me.
It is what it is.
Man, oh, man.
Oh, it's this stuff.
Dros 2, which means there's a Dros 1.
How do I get to Dros 1?
Oh, that's a question.
This place also has this weird fire.
Go right.
Okay, so what's happening with this thing?
If I blow it up, we get minus luck, which is bad.
So we must do something else with it.
I don't know what, though.
Oh, wait.
Maybe we need to access it from behind.
Does that make sense?
Let me see.
Can I potentially get in there?
Maybe there's a way to get behind that room and then access...
Look at these poops!
These poops are smiling.
Something's off with that.
Wait, what?
What is that?
Are they my friends?
Are we friends?
We're friends.
Okay.
I'm gonna destroy this.
You're not gonna hurt me, right?
I'm scared.
Weird.
The fact that the mirror is showing up on the map, though, makes me think we have to do something there.
Like, maybe it's like a Mario thing, you know?
You jump in the painting, but it's a mirror.
You look inside your mind, your own reflection.
Poop barrels?
Or, yeah, not barrels.
These guys are not too bad.
Oh, wait, these are friends.
Okay, I'm gonna try and touch this bucket.
Okay, I don't take damage.
Good.
Confirmed.
Get boogered.
Get boogered, nerd.
That was my last key.
Contagion.
It is actually a good one.
It is a good one, but it's not that good.
Actually, it is pretty good.
I think I'll take it.
Yeah.
Also, what's that button do?
Donation?
Wait, what?
Why is that there?
We gotta experiment with this.
Take all my money.
Okay, it took all my money.
I thought maybe something special would happen.
Maybe there's a breakpoint, you know, after X amount of coins, something happens.
This guy is supposedly poisoned now, right?
Oh, look at that key down there.
Nice.
I needed that.
Oh, that's huge.
Let me try and understand this.
So, yeah, look.
So, one of my rules.
I'm actually gonna write it down now.
We're gonna write it down.
Uh, where's my there?
So, we're gonna make a little section for this.
Secret room.
Rule one.
I want to say rule one is always sort of centralized.
Rule two.
This one I'm not sure about.
Favors, uh, wait, no, no, actually, I don't want to mislead my future self.
What do we know?
Two, uh, rule two.
Two types of secret rooms.
There's a bright and a gray one, right?
And rule three can be close together.
I don't know if they can be really far apart.
I haven't actually paid attention to that very much.
But let's just try and pay attention to that.
Okay, uh, what now?
I think we go to the boss.
No, we have one more room to explore.
I also don't want to leave yet because I'm curious about that mirror.
I think maybe it's related to the secret rooms.
Why,
how come people are not getting a contagion?
Maybe they are.
I don't see a visual effect though.
Ah, the first enemy killed, right, okay.
There's also another item that, uh, poisons everyone in the room as soon as you enter.
This is not that one.
This is the one that sort of spreads poison to everyone else.
Like a chain reaction.
Okay, so I think if I destroy these buckets, it's essentially like destroying poop piles, because there's poop inside the buckets, right?
Three coins is not worth it to waste the key on, so I'm not gonna do that.
Let's go to... ah, man.
Let's go back to the mirror.
I kind of want to blow it up, man.
Like, it's like an exchange, you know.
You get minus luck, but something else happens.
That's what it has to mean.
Minus seven luck.
Okay, let's see if anything changed now.
Nothing has changed.
Not here, at least.
I'm checking all the rooms.
I could blow this up, actually.
Maybe there's something in there.
Ah, you know what?
Just donate everything.
I really should start donating money to that.
Like, more than I'm doing now.
Also, if you can hear, like, vibrations and loud sounds, it's my washing machine going crazy.
I don't see anything in here.
Kind of want to enter the curse room, but I also kind of don't, because I need all the HP I can get right now for the boss.
Okay, so we broke the mirror.
Now we're gonna fight the boss.
Let's see if anything changed in here.
Okay, well, that's kind of a new boss, right?
Maybe not.
Looks very similar.
Okay.
The boogers here are gonna be huge.
Yeah.
Good boogers.
Okay, he's gonna do that now.
That's cool.
Yeah.
Oh, the poison though.
Nice.
Another health.
Man, I really want to take this.
So far, I really have had no need to re-roll.
I've gotten good items.
But I guess, okay, this one doesn't give luck or anything.
But some of these health items also give damage, so I could re-roll.
Let's just do it.
Okay, I mean, some extra damage is kind of nice, actually.
I appreciate it.
Now, unfortunately, can't get in here, because I don't have enough bombs.
Ah, crap.
On the next run, I'm gonna start noticing which floors have these things here, because I don't remember which floor I'm on now.
I need to remember what items I need on which floor.
Yeah, let's keep going.
So this, okay, so that was floor three.
Right.
Okay, let me write that down.
Uh,
let's write that... let me just copy this one, I guess.
Floors.
Uh, floor three has a door that can be broken with two bombs.
And I'm pretty sure floor one has a door that requires one key.
Uh, to progress to... what was it called?
Downpour?
Uh, that can be broken with two bombs to get to.
What was this place called?
We don't know, okay.
Ah, that's fine.
Oh, no, wait, this is, uh, this is just a normal one.
Caves or whatever.
Oh, that's evil!
That guy up there, though.
In the corner.
Crazy.
Oh, the healing, I can't get it.
Ah, why you gotta do me dirty like that, man?
That's horrible.
Oh, man.
The poison's so important there.
Contagion.
I gotta find flying or something, jump or, you know.
Flying ultra safe.
Let's go all the way across here first.
You can actually see the contagion spread.
You see it jump from one to the next.
Yeah, chain reaction!
Yeah, look at that!
Ah, that's awesome.
Ooh, that was a bit scary.
Uh, I think I'm gonna, I'm not gonna risk it for these two coins, not yet.
I'm a little bit too scared.
Okay, not too bad.
Are we done in here?
All right.
Man, oh
my god.
Oh, the healing is so crucial.
I'm holding on to dear life right now.
The first one we kill has to spread.
Ah, well, it's not gonna happen, is it?
Unfortunate.
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
I'm trying to play really safe here.
One at a time.
We're playing slow.
This is what it takes to get a win streak going, man.
We gotta start paying more attention, you know, instead of going gong ho.
That is fun in itself, but I really want this win streak here.
Nice.
It's huge.
Yo, this item is actually mega fun.
Ringworm.
Spectral tears.
I don't think so.
I like my current booger.
Uh, I can get in there.
Ah, very nice.
Spread your disease.
I could get in there as well.
I think I'm gonna do it from here, just in case there's a secret.
There is not.
Oh, man.
See, now I stand as a statue.
I want everyone to come to this room and join me for this lemon party.
Oh, it doesn't even last forever, okay.
The party has to end.
Oh.
They call me the sniper.
Uh, boss with one and a half HP.
Huh, maybe a little risky.
Actually, bosses are a lot of times easier than rooms.
But I just don't feel good right now.
I need to do this.
Fuck.
No way.
Wait, I had one and a half hearts.
I thought I would be at at least half a heart there.
That didn't uh, compute for me.
He must have done one full heart of damage per shot.
That's crazy.
I thought that only happened in the womb and shit or the uterus.
Okay, well, let's uh, migrate over to a polyon then.
This is my new favorite character.
I love his active.
And I have these goofy wings.
At least I think they're wings.
Either that or shoulder pads.
Uh, XL.
So this is a big floor.
Come on, now.
Okay.
Unfortunate end to that, uh, run just now.
Like, I'm just in a corner.
I don't know what to do in that situation.
Like, they forced me into a corner and then I'm just stuck there.
Um, we go in here.
Okay, see, I don't like this.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna consume it.
Okay, and it's gonna give us stats.
Damage and shot speed.
Nice!
We also have a tinted rock.
But no bombs.
Wait, I thought I could walk through there!
I misread the map.
I had my whole plan already, like, laid out.
I was gonna walk up here and then lead them this way, but there was a hole.
That wasn't big enough.
Unfortunate.
Man, this is already looking bad, you know?
It's not looking good!
No money either.
Shit.
Not even two coins for that HP.
Man.
I'm not asking for much here.
Just a bit of HP.
You also just start with two hearts on this guy.
Uh-oh.
Is this our end?
Is this how it all ends?
Why is he not doing anything?
Oh, wait, it's this.
I thought it was the guy that did the diagonal lasers.
Just play patient.
It's the way to win this.
Focus.
Not over till it's over.
Ooh, that's scary.
Oh, man, no healing?
But we have bombs.
Maybe we can get healing with that.
I don't think so.
You know what I could do?
I could blow up the donation machine.
Get a bit of money by the heart.
And you know what?
I donated last run, so it's okay.
I can do it.
It's allowed.
I'll be taking that.
We're not gonna buy the 5.1 yet.
Not yet, because check it out.
On...
I was about to say, on the first floor, you don't have any, uh, devil chance anyway, but it seems like I do.
So now I'm confused about that.
I thought that only happened from floor two.
I'm actually so confused about that right now.
What the hell?
No.
No, run.
Dude, how am I gonna survive this?
Spread the needle!
Okay, we got a lot of real estate on the left.
Damage is decent.
Okay, got a key.
A bit of healing.
Sometimes you find...
Eternal hearts in these, you know?
Or was that a poop?
Maybe that was a poop.
I'm gonna peek in here.
Oh, man.
How am I gonna do this?
Oh my gosh.
Nice.
Long range on this guy.
Systematic.
Not bad.
Careful.
Is that what I think it is?
Release a giant fart that poise... Oh, I don't want to do that.
I don't want to do that.
So wait, I need to understand how this works again with the actives.
Consumes any pedestal items in the room.
And triggers the effects of all previously consumed active items.
Okay.
And the effect here is to release a giant fart.
Poisons, petrifies, knocks back, and deals 100 damage to all enemies.
Destroys obstacles and breaks open doors.
Whoa, actually.
That's pretty cool.
But I guess to really optimize this, I would take this first.
Use it.
Somewhere.
To break open a door, and then come back for the other one, and then consume it.
Like that.
Now we go back.
I could have saved it for the boss, I guess, but...
Nice!
All right.
Still only one heart, though.
That's scary.
Any tinted rocks?
I think I saw a tinted rock somewhere.
And I have four bombs.
Four coins as well, so we're definitely gonna do this.
A lucky penny!
Very nice.
I'm just instinctively, ooh, running away from those things as soon as I destroy them now.
Or open them.
Hansel and Gretel!
Healing!
Oh!
Clutch!
Okay.
Ah, this is easy.
It's just about being patient.
Nice.
Bam, bam, bam, bam, bam.
Uh, nothing of interest in here.
This is a very nice floor.
Double excel, double excel!
Load up.
Strength!
Plus one health and a lot of goodies.
I need to get better at using cards.
I almost never use them because I keep thinking I'm gonna save this for a rainy day, you know, and then I never use it.
It spawns a beggar.
I have 22 coins, man.
I could, uh...
Then again, there's also a shop.
Let me go back to the shop first.
Yeah.
Maybe look for secrets.
I think that could be a secret.
Maybe here.
Let me see from the other room.
There's an obstacle.
I don't think there is actually, but only three bombs left.
It's a bit risky.
I would almost say this is more probable here.
I believe.
Ah, should have gone for the other room.
Okay, we're gonna save the bombs now.
So because this is...
Excel, there should be another shop, I guess?
Or no, there's definitely two treasure rooms.
There's gonna be two bosses.
Right?
Uh, maybe worth it, actually.
Yeah.
I'm gonna take this heart as well.
And now we're out of money.
I think that was worth it.
Maybe one more attempt at a secret.
No, no, no.
We're gonna save the bombs.
Always have at least two bombs.
This is the new rule.
Simply because of getting to the doors that require them, right?
Always have two bombs, always one key.
This is the plan.
And there was a tinted rock somewhere.
Could also have been the last run, though, because I finished so fast, you know?
Maybe my memory's playing tricks on me.
Tinted rock.
Was it in here?
No?
There it is.
Lovely.
Actually insane.
Wait, I used my bomb!
I broke the one rule I had.
Can we buy another bomb?
God damn it, man.
I had one rule for myself.
Ah, we can go into the... we can go to the curse room.
We have the blue heart buffer.
I think it's worth.
Little bastard!
This better be good.
No, this better be good.
The other one better contain some good shit.
No!
Let's not forget we have strength.
We're gonna use it as soon as we take damage.
So heal up.
No forgetting cards today, baby.
That's right.
Kind of scary, though.
We have two bosses to go through.
Gimme the...
This guy's fine.
It's not a big deal.
Come on.
Just chillax.
Let's try and get into this cheese configuration.
There it is.
That's the cheese configuration.
Ah, we messed it up a little bit.
So we're gonna go up here and do that.
That's the cheese configuration.
Ah, I messed it up again.
Yeah, nice.
There's also tinted rock here.
You know what?
Since I already used one of the bombs, I think I can allow myself to do it.
Uh, ooh, that's very nice.
I gotta take that.
I don't even want to consume that at all.
Bomb the shit out of that.
Oh!
Wow!
I mean, we have a buffer now.
Not even Seagal is gonna have anything to say about that.
I have to remember, when he dies, he's gonna shoot spectral tears.
I always forget that they're spectral, and then I get hit by it.
Oh, little guy's angry now.
This is a cheese configuration possibility, though.
There is a way to... Oh, okay.
He's fast.
Cheese!
Nice.
That was good.
Oh my god, he ran into me.
I ran into him.
We both ran into each other.
Get ready.
There it is.
That's a lot of damage.
I mean, you can't say no to that.
And again, I wonder what happens if I consume this.
Hmm...
I can't pass it up.
Even if I get good stats, is it really gonna be better than 1.69 damage?
I doubt it.
So, yeah.
Okay, we are done here.
What the fuck?
What do you want?
Let's go.
Okay.
Curse of the Unknown.
That is the one where we can't see the HP.
Yeah.
Okay, uh, obviously there's something going on here.
Uh, I'm not gonna blow it up.
I don't like having minus luck.
Maybe we need to somehow bring a poop bucket to it.
The poop bucket is kind of big here, you know?
People go crazy for that.
I don't know how we would transport it, though.
Can't really bring items from one room to another.
I'm just spitballing right now.
You guys gonna blow up, I think?
No?
Okay.
Just playing it safe.
Okay, that's good.
I like that.
Maybe we step.
Probably not, though, because we have so many blue hearts.
And busy boys?
I like the way I'm approaching this right now.
This is good.
Uh, Bumbo.
Familiar that wanders around consuming coin pickups from the ground.
Levels up as it consumes coins, gaining new abilities that can damage enemies and spawn items.
Uh...
I think I'd rather just consume them.
Also, I wonder...
There's two pedestals in here.
So, am I gonna consume both?
Consumes any pedestal items in the room.
Hey, I mean, come on.
That sounds good.
0.5 tiers, 0.2 shot speed.
Doesn't feel like I consumed two items, but okay.
Unless one of those was an active that I didn't know.
Which means the next time I use this, maybe something happens, you know, that we can't predict.
I need to be ready for this.
Also, I forgot that we are pooping with this now.
I could use it offensively if the situation calls for it.
I'm probably not gonna have the presence of mind to do that while I'm still getting used to all these new enemies and areas here.
Just trying to process all that, you know.
I can't be thinking about all that.
Bomb for me.
Okay, dude, I gotta go close the door.
It's too cold here.
One second.
Okay, so I can't actually open up close the door because there's a cat in it in front of it.
I have to walk all the way around the building and close the door from the other side.
And I also gotta quickly turn off the washing machine.
So we're gonna take a break.
I'll see you in like seven minutes.
All right, I'm back.
I'm sorry about that.
That was a really horrible and unfortunate situation.
It's not very well thought through with the with the cat in it and the way the door is working.
It's kind of bad the way I've set it up.
All right, everything's okay though.
Jackie got a little frightened because I suddenly appeared on the other side of the door where she usually doesn't see me.
So she's like, who's that?
And I was like, Jackie, it's me.
He's like, oh, okay.
Okay, here we go.
Cheers.
Let's go.
What was I doing here?
That's right.
I was winning.
I only have four coins.
So maybe I don't enter there.
There's a curse room.
I could do that.
Oh, I don't remember how much HP I have, though.
This is the problem.
Yeah, let's just go.
It... Turdlet?
What a name.
I feel bad for this guy.
Wait, can I take damage in this creep?
No.
Oh, but I slide around in the creep.
Oh my God, the Turd is sliding on the floor.
It reminds me of my time in America.
I had something similar happen.
It sounds crazy when I say it like that, but it's the truth.
Uh, stapler.
1.26 damage.
Yeah.
Why not?
I like it.
We could go for this.
I think I may.
Oh God.
Oi, nice.
I mean, whoa, wait, wait, wait.
If I... What happens if I consume in here?
Wait a minute.
If I consume in here, I get them for free.
Fuck.
Okay, well, I guess that would have been broken.
That would have been massively broken.
Uh, yeah, fuck.
Sacrificial dagger.
Orbital knife familiar that deals heavy contact damage and blocks enemy shots.
Uh...
I'm trying to remember how much HP we have.
I... man, I don't know.
It's not a lot, I don't think.
Wait, that's not true.
We found a bunch of blue hearts, didn't we?
So I think it's okay.
I take this.
Wait, now this turned into blue hearts and one red heart.
That has to mean...
that...
No, never mind, actually.
I don't know what that means.
I'm not sure what that means.
But we're gonna go in here, obviously.
Blow it up.
Wait, before I go, was there anything else I need to do here?
You have one key for the shop.
There's also the freaking mirror.
So now I've killed the boss.
Let's check on the mirror.
Maybe something changed.
Show me the good stuff.
Oh, wait, healing.
Oh, I'm full.
I guess I don't have many red hearts anyway.
Uh...
Let's try and destroy these fires.
There's always blue fires in there.
Okay, I don't know.
Kind of wanted to try the, uh, the boom, the big mega boom, mega bean in there.
Oh, well.
Curse room.
I could go in there.
Let's do it.
Uh-oh.
Money, though.
Okay, this was totally worth.
If I open this, I can't get to the shop.
If I get to the shop, I have 10 coins.
Questions, questions.
I think it's better to...
Open this.
Yeah, it was!
Not bad.
Now we go to the shop with 15 coins.
Unfortunately, no 15 dollar item.
Wait a minute.
If I consume in here...
I was thinking I take battery, I use my uh, active.
That's gonna consume this, right?
Destroy all pickups on the ground in the current room when picked up and grants one blue spider or fly for each... I mean...
I'm gonna...
Ah, but then again, do I need to buy it first?
I wonder, because it would be kind of broken if I can just do this.
Let's say there's a 15 cent item and a 10 cent item.
If I use this in here...
Like, I can't just get both benefits, right?
That would be crazy.
Yeah.
Yeah, no, we're gonna move on.
We're gonna go in here, of course.
Show me what's good.
No tinted rocks.
Down the hatch.
Mine's XL.
Okay.
Oh, we only have one red heart.
Oh.
Ah, ah.
Doesn't feel good, man.
Two treasure rooms, though.
I think we should go towards that immediately.
Uh, what's the point of this room?
Okay.
Weird.
Oh, no.
I'm not equipped for this sort of thing.
Uh, okay.
Let's go in here.
Oh, god.
I am so scared of these guys.
They're gonna wake up, right?
Or what's happening?
Jackie, please.
Not right now.
Oh, you can't be there.
I just have so many distractions right now.
Fucking hell.
Is this a new song?
Sounds new to me.
Straight for the treasure rooms.
Grab the keys.
Oh, man.
I mean, what do you even do here?
I think we're done.
I'm not gonna win this.
Oh, I tried to time the fucking thing.
Oh, my god.
These levels are crazy hard.
I can't win at all in those places.
Uh, what was the other one I wanted to try?
Eden.
Let's go Eden.
Isaac failed.
Apollyon failed.
It's time for Eden.
Can he do it?
Sulfur.
Prince Brimstone for the current room.
Okay, that's not bad, actually.
Activating twice, gives a better one, and friendzoned, unfortunately.
It is what it is.
No, but no red hearts, dude.
Shit.
Oh, my god.
Um, gain invincibility.
Man, that's terrible.
Like, who's that for?
You can't attack with it, so it's kind of useless.
At least for combat.
Boom.
Nah, that's not that good.
No like that.
My familiar is actually a decent damage dealer.
Especially for situations like that, you see?
I can shoot through rocks.
I kind of need that blue heart, because I only have blue hearts.
Which means we can't heal easily.
The good news, though, is that we're gonna have a higher chance of getting angel slash demon.
Simply because we don't have any red hearts, right?
So there's an upside.
Focus on one at a time.
I almost activated the brimstone.
And that is the wiggle worm.
Ah, is that something I like?
Actually, it's not that bad.
I like it.
Spectral tears as well.
I mean...
That is a lot of safety there, you know?
Wait, there's a chest I missed.
Oh, there's two chests, right.
Right.
So luck, we can just shoot them through the rocks now.
Not bad.
I think we just go for the boss immediately.
Activate the brim.
Kick his ass.
Oh, that looks funny.
The wiggle brim.
I really thought you were gonna charge me there.
And there it is.
Yeah, that's huge.
Love finding that.
Okay, so that takes a key.
But I have one bomb that I can potentially use to find a secret room with.
See, this room I'm a little confused about.
There's technically not an obstruction near the wall back there.
But there is an obstruction here.
So I don't know if that would count as an obstruction.
I could use one bomb to destroy that.
Or to get the heart.
I think maybe getting the heart is more important.
Just saying.
To also destroy this could be a secret and then get the coin as well.
I think that may be the better gamble.
Fuck.
Well, it was a gamble.
It's okay.
We have a red heart at least.
That makes me feel better.
Let's go.
Now...
Downpour is what this is.
So this is like...
Floor 2, right?
Let me see what this is.
I'm drowsy.
Okay, well...
Let's listen to that music while we note things down.
Floors...
Floor 2...
Oh, we know this already, right?
So I'm just gonna say this is Downpour.
It's Downpour or the other one, right?
There's two options.
Down we go.
Oh, that sounds weird.
I liked it.
I'm gonna shoot these through the rocks.
Oh, yeah.
Beautiful.
Very safe.
Oh, we can't destroy that.
Okay, so now there's a purple and a blue fire.
There's always two fires and a mirror, right?
I...
Why is this highlighted on the map?
Mirrors reflection.
Do we need to reflect something?
Do we need to do... I don't know, man.
So much poop in the air.
Not worth it to get that coin.
How was I in range?
That felt like bullshit.
What do you mean?
I was like 10 kilometers away.
What?
That made no sense.
Two items.
Wait, why are we getting a choice here?
Is it because...
Is it... is it because it's XL?
Does that mean there's a choice now?
I don't like Finger very much.
I'm gonna take this.
Taurus!
Oh, that's not the one I was thinking of.
Less speed?
While in a room with enemies, Isaac gains a stacking speed bonus.
Let me gain this speed.
Five seconds invincibility.
Heals contact damage, but tears are disabled.
Yeah, okay.
Not a big fan of that one.
I thought it was the one that made me eat rocks.
Thank you.
Four bombs.
We could do some hunting for secrets.
Good night.
Spectral tears are not the same as the, uh, piercing tears, unfortunately.
Oh, we got a...
Okay, so watch out.
This is the fire, right?
It's not gonna be affected by bombs.
But maybe it is affected by something else.
Ooh!
Nice!
Very nice.
Good shit.
Whoa!
Leave them down to the right and then go.
I handled that pretty well.
Very good.
Okay, so let's try and get behind the...
Oh, I was about to say behind the mirror, but that's not here.
That's up there.
I don't think you can actually get behind it.
Plus two damage for the room.
Turdlet!
Once again.
I'm just gonna go ahead and do this.
Whoa!
That was close!
I'll be slipping!
Oh, right.
Placenta, very nice.
That's a huge upgrade.
I'm not too, uh, unhappy about my situation, though.
Also, there should be another treasure room somewhere, if I'm not completely mistaken.
Oh god, get away from me.
That was bad.
I should not have taken damage there.
It does not go down, unfortunately.
Oh, imagine if it, like, slid across the center.
Into my... into my arms.
Whoa!
What?
Hold on, hold on, what?
Point eleven-five damage!
Massively increases tear damage and decreases fire rate.
Tears that destroy an enemy continue traveling on with their remaining damage.
Wow!
I mean, point one nine, our one point nine tears is not that bad of a loss compared to what we have.
I'll be taking that.
Okay, it's very slow.
But it's gonna pack a punch.
Right?
So maybe it's okay.
Oh man!
He explodes?
Too bad.
I should not have used my last key.
I'm on autopilot right now.
Fuck!
I hate when I'm on autopilot.
Uh, well, okay.
Okay, so let's think about this.
What is there to do?
Uh, there's this room, curse room.
There's a button!
Health up, health up.
Ah.
I, the only thing I can do is blow it up, man.
I can blow it up.
And...
Oh, I don't know.
Something's going on with that.
Maybe it's one of those you need to have only certain hearts or something.
There's also this thing.
Wait, if I walk into that...
Okay, is there something going on with this?
Can we interact with the mirror now?
That's like the only other thing I can do on this floor.
Can I do something now?
Oh wait, what?
Oh, we're on the other side?
Oh yeah, but wait, we were gonna die in one hit.
This is actually not good.
Except it is, because this is awesome.
But you know what I mean.
Okay!
I really should have just thought about it like that from the get-go, you know?
Like, what can I actually do on this floor?
Um...
I don't dare go into that room if I die from it.
I do a lot of damage.
Jesus Christ.
Everything is sort of...
Wait a minute, is the music reversed?
Is it mirrored?
Mirror dimension.
Okay, so this is gonna blow me up.
Okay, so I wonder what the deal is with this place then.
No items?
Dude, what?
Man, what is this?
This place sucks!
Unless they're invisible.
Wait a minute, is this actually a mirror image?
I don't recall the layout of the other place.
I don't recall.
Yo, what if I walk into the fire again?
I'm gonna wait with that until we have cleared everything.
I want to see what happens.
Shit.
Oh my god.
I'm playing as if one hit will kill me.
Hoi!
What was that?
Oh, I don't like that actually.
I really should be using the devil if I'm in trouble.
Okay.
Uh, I also have brimstone.
Let's go.
Oh, he's turtle it again.
Wait, I'm charging super slow now.
Oh, yeah, right because more damage less tears makes sense.
No!
Fuck dude, I hate this.
I hate walking into the thing and becoming a thing.
God damn it.
There's gotta be like a crazy reward for this.
Otherwise, why would you ever want to do that, right?
There's gotta be something on the other side.
Okay, dude, here's what we're gonna do.
You ready?
Watch this.
We're going in with a sasal and we're clearing out the fucking mirror dimension.
I'm had it with this shit.
That's right.
How did I take damage?
How did I just take damage?
I think I stepped on some poop.
What is that?
Yeah, that's an amazing item.
One of the best items in the game.
There's also a tinted rock there.
Can't forget.
Never forgetty.
I'm ready.
Are you ready?
Kill them all.
Dude, I'm gonna fucking smack these fools with a sasal.
I can fly.
I have to remember I can fly.
Another tinted rock.
Is it gonna be one of those a million tinted rocks, no bombs situations?
Hope not.
Got a bomb.
Let's do it here.
Dude, I'm so happy, man.
A secret has been discovered.
You know, I should be noting this down, actually.
Let's just note that down right now.
I need to really organize these notes.
This is a fucking mess.
Where would I put this?
Observations.
Okay, listen up, pal.
Become spirit.
Mirror yourself, fool.
Surely that will make sense later.
I didn't know what to write.
First thing that came to mind.
What do you want?
I love just staying where they can't hit me as a sasal.
There's a certain feeling about that.
Pin!
One, two, three, four.
Got him.
Uhhhh.
That was my excited collab.
What a W.
I want that so bad as well.
Can we find the money?
Is that a third tinted rock?
Fuck.
I was about to say I need more bananas.
I need bombs.
I don't know why I said bananas.
Uh, we can go in here now.
We also have the fool, right?
So...
Oh my god.
Embarrassing.
Wooden cross.
Hey, why not?
Doubles affects most cars.
How does that work with the fool?
The sun?
Okay, you know what?
I'll take this because I'm gonna use the cross to take damage on my way out, right?
Okay, uh, that's it for now.
There's nothing else to do here.
Maybe there's a bomb to buy in the shop?
I may have missed that.
There's absolutely no way we can buy the big item anyway.
Okay, fuck.
I could re-roll.
Hoping for a bomb.
This may be dumb.
It's okay.
Sometimes you get shit luck, you know?
It happens.
It is what it is.
Wait, we can't even go in here!
Uh, wait, that's gotta be, uh, hold on a minute, hold on a minute, hold on a minute.
I- the key!
Does the sun give me a key?
Reveals the map, but I don't have a- Bomb, so I can't go to the secret room.
Oh man, there's a library as well.
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
What is this cock block?
Oh, this is the most painful first floor I've ever had in my life.
Oh, that's terrible.
Well, we still have a chance.
We can maybe get to, uh, downport two or whatever.
Or draws two.
Uh, the sun is in our possession.
Oh, almost hit me there.
And now we get a key.
Hey guys.
Playing it safe.
No need to go fast.
Nice.
Ooh, is that Ludo Vico?
It is!
This one is good on Azazel.
It is very good.
Yeah.
Yeah, we're back.
Oh, I have- I've missed you.
That's okay.
We need to calm down a bit.
Give me that.
Excitement overload.
Oh, this is amazing.
It feels so good.
Oh, yes.
Beautiful.
I'm just gonna sit here and hide and play ultra safe.
Dude, mirror dimension is gonna eat my ass.
I didn't mean that.
What I mean is, it's not gonna stand a chance against my current technique.
I'm gonna win.
Let's go!
You shall haunt no more, sir.
Nice.
Oh my god.
It's just so good.
I like this one.
Speed, damage.
Ooh, less range.
That doesn't matter.
Nice.
Less luck.
Who cares?
Great.
That's great.
And I definitely want to go in here.
Ooh, man.
Oh, man.
Uh, I like that one.
We take it.
Hell, yeah.
Uh, we're not gonna go yet.
Not yet.
What?
Well, gotta go south.
Holy shit, it's disgusting.
The amount of damage I deal right now.
Is that?
No, it's not data miner, unfortunately.
Paralysis.
Add it for me, son.
I am actually gonna go in here, because we got the cross.
That was a very underwhelming room.
Hey, dude, the cross is so good.
One bomb left.
I'm gonna save it, because the rule is...
We gotta have at least two bombs.
I know I don't have two bombs, but...
You gotta start with one before you can get to two, right?
Okay, here we go.
You got a key, though.
What do you want?
I can't lose with this setup, by the way.
S .A.
So, Ludovico, that's my home field.
I am unkillable in this state.
Look at the reflection on the floor.
That's neat.
It does block a lot of the screen.
Oh, wait, I wonder if...
Oh, with the mouse, though.
Yo, I gotta... I... hold on, I gotta try that.
I gotta try that.
Oh, it's gonna feel weird.
Maybe I'm not gonna...
Okay, so here's the mirror.
Mirror acquired.
Uh, don't go in there yet.
Oh, yeah, I can fly.
Don't forget it.
What we got here?
Boiled, baby!
Launches scattered bursts of shots at random intervals.
I don't like that.
I'm gonna take the unknown.
There's another bean!
What's the difference?
This is a fart that poisons enemies and reflects...
Come on, man.
I'd rather have this, actually.
You know what?
No, no, this is better.
Because I can sit in a corner, right?
Control my thing, and then when projectiles come close, I poop it away.
This is the setup, guys.
This is how I will dominate.
Tears and shot speed.
It happens.
Not that that matters.
Actually, tears doesn't matter.
Oh, yeah.
So, okay.
Maybe I don't like, actually, the mouse.
I'm gonna go without mouse again.
I think it's just gonna confuse me.
I want to play it safe.
Okay, here we go.
We got a fire.
Uh,
secret rule.
Ooh, I do like that.
Take me.
Show me what's good.
Oi, that's nice!
And Jaira as well?
Oh!
I mean...
Oh, I didn't realize I only had one bomb.
I messed up bad!
Wait, I can't leave.
I can leave.
Imagine if you get stuck in there with no bombs.
We're gonna use it when we find a bunch of hearts.
Yeah, I wish I had bombs now.
Fuck it.
Let's go.
The Rainmaker.
Oh, yeah, I'm the Painmaker!
Ludo Vico!
Oh, you're dead already!
Feels amazing.
Now, I wish I had bombs.
Five random cards.
We could get bombs from this.
Teleport to the boss room.
Uh, if the boss room isn't cleared, Garant's won Soulheart.
Okay.
Where's the other one?
The stars!
That one was...
If there's a planetarium, teleport to it unless there's a treasure room.
If the treasure room is unexplored, choose between two item pedestals.
Whoa!
Wait.
I didn't realize it did that.
That's information.
That's new information for me.
That's cool.
I kind of want to keep this, then.
Uh, but of course we gotta use the Jira first.
Let's keep exploring here in case we find bombs.
Uh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
There's a... Oh, wait, I can fly.
Haha!
Hey!
We got a bomb!
What do I need the bomb for?
Was it to... I don't... Actually, I don't want to open that door, because I'm going into the mirror dimension.
So maybe I blow this up?
I need to be really careful what I do with this bomb.
That's all I'm saying.
In fact, let's go to the curse room, since we still have the cross.
Yep, I like it.
I don't like that.
Shit.
I was hoping for some hearts.
Uh, right, so we're just gonna walk through here.
There's a fight room, but it's closed.
Okay, let's go to the shop.
Seven coins!
Damn, it's useless.
Okay, here's the plan.
We are gonna grab the...
box here.
Underwear!
I mean, that's two out of three on Yes Mother.
Whatever that means.
I still don't understand that one, but that's probably good.
This one re... Oh man, I could have done this, revealed the map, and then bombed myself into a secret room.
That would have been a play as well.
Then think about that.
I'm trying to think about my steps here carefully.
Uh, boss room, the hermit...
Wait, what?
Teleport to the shop prevents greed from appearing.
Whoa, I didn't know that did that either!
All these teleport cards are better than I thought.
The fool doubles Isaac's keys!
Let's use that now.
Okay, so now we have... Oh my god, what is this one?
Teleport to boss room.
I'm gonna take the one that...
I'll take Jera, man.
I think it's better.
Let's go, uh, jump into a fire.
It's like, okay, we leave behind our corporeal form, and we are actually like a ghost.
We are the soul.
Okay.
Maybe you have to be pure to enter this dimension.
We have to see yourself for who you really are or something.
I don't know.
All right, here we go, here we go.
I'm scared as shit.
At least I'm flying right...
Oh no.
Can I unbecome, uh...
Wait, go in.
What is this?
The fuck is that?
All right.
Nothing.
I'm not gonna enter that room.
Look at the question mark, it's reversed.
Actually, all the icons are reversed.
The treasure room is reversed, too.
And the... that's crazy.
There's someone in here.
No, there's not.
Stay in the corner.
We stay far away from everyone.
I've never been this scared ever before.
Okay.
What's that?
Knife piece one.
When assembled, forms a knife familiar that can...
Oh, forms a knife familiar that can charge across the room to damage enemies and can open a fleshy door.
Ooh!
Peepy door!
We got to find the other pieces.
That is 100% peepy door.
Oh, no!
Don't kill me like that.
Oh, my god.
Imagine if I died like that.
Shop room?
Are we good in here?
Okay.
I really want to try and touch that, but...
Not yet.
I knew it was gonna come... I knew, I knew it.
I really should be going into a corner like this because I can fly anyway and then just, you know, little Vico.
That is the strategy.
Load that up.
Nothing?
Okay.
Sure.
Okay, we gotta, we gotta kill this boss, man.
The rain may- Okay, here we go.
Wish me luck.
He's dead!
Yeah!
Mouse pearls, range, and luck, and a soul heart, or...
Depression.
Sure.
I'll take this, thank you.
Yes, mother- Oh, oh, oh!
I didn't even realize that was a yes, mother item.
So, what did we get from that?
Why do I keep looking in the inventory as if that's gonna tell me?
It never does.
I don't know what we just got.
Oh, wait, the knife!
That's what we got.
It's like a weird familiar that's following me.
Uh, so wait, what do we do here?
I guess we go through the mirror again to get out.
But what was the point of this place?
Maybe to find the knife piece.
Oh, nice!
We are no longer afflicted by the one-hit death situation.
That's awesome.
But where are we gonna find the other pieces?
This needs to be assembled, of course.
Wait, I have two bombs now.
Right?
So, maybe I can use that somewhere smart?
I know what I can do.
This...
I thought that was a second secret room.
I was lied to.
I think we're done here.
Um...
Wait, I have a Jarrah, though.
It feels bad leaving all these cards behind.
Hey, I can go in here now!
I got two bombs!
Yo!
Let's do that!
Nice, but wait, wait, wait, wait.
Uh, the fool... this one was...
The... I'm taking this.
No, I'm taking this, actually.
Fuck Jarrah!
We're doing the stars!
And that one was...
Planetarium, and if there isn't, if the treasure room is unexplored, we get two item pedestals.
Hell yeah!
That's the plan.
Dude, this is awesome!
Let's go!
And we're also doing good on time.
Kinda.
Not that we need to, but you know.
Teleport!
The stars... three pedestals?!
Monstro's lung?
Tears become a charge?
Ew.
Nope.
Uh, heals... nope.
It's gotta be the middle one.
Flush.
Oh!
Maybe I like that more.
Actually, not too fast!
Flush these fools!
Oh, this guy did not get flush.
If they're on the ground, the flush is not affecting them.
We got two keys, no bombs.
Why has bombs been such a problem?
In this run, huh?
Voodoo hit.
Spawns an additional curse room on each new floor when possible.
Improved layouts and rewards within curse rooms also causes one coin to spawn in each curse room.
Uh, are we gonna go full curse?
I think you should, especially because we have...
the cross, right?
That absorbs damage.
I like...
I like it.
At first, I was like, why would I want more curse rooms?
But if they're, you know, better at better rewards, then I can see a...
a reason.
Flush me.
Oh!
Right.
Actually, I should be using that to destroy rocks, right?
There's no reason not to.
Sometimes there's blue hearts in there.
Okay, that's good enough.
Let's go in here.
Anymore?
No.
Cool pill.
Uh, wait.
We only had one red heart anyway, right?
So this is actually fine.
You don't care.
Nice.
Doesn't matter for me.
We're cool.
Get rid of these fires.
Uh, bomb for me.
I'm playing it so safe.
A credit card makes any purchasable items and pickups in the current room free.
Whoa.
Oh, I thought it was an active.
God damn it.
Well, that's useless, I guess, right?
What's the point of that then?
That's like the most useless item.
Ah!
It's a card!
Right!
Okay.
I see now.
I get it.
Should I flush these fools?
I think so.
Uh, what?
Oh.
Okay, not bad.
Lucky penny as well.
No keys anymore.
My play is so safe.
Uh, what is this?
Like, I don't understand the point of the making the things on the floor there.
Oh, maybe if you can't fly.
I'm just not used to hanging out with plebeians who can't fly, you know.
That's all.
I am in the fly-only club.
Uh, wait, wait, wait.
Okay, so if you can't fly, you can now get over there.
I think we just go for the boss.
Hornfel.
This guy is tough as hell if you don't have a lot of damage.
I mean, that was amazing.
Perfection?
What?
I didn't realize we had perfection.
That's amazing.
I mean, the wooden cross is pretty good, though, but...
Perfection.
Wait, what?
Two items?
Why are there two items here?
Because of perfection, maybe.
Plus five bombs, they deal contact damage.
Explosions leave behind fires.
Not gonna affect me, I think, because I'm flying, right?
Grants immunity to damage from... Oh yeah, well, in that case, it's not.
Sure, I'll take it.
So, a lot of luck.
So what we want now is to have modifiers that rely on luck.
That's gonna be the big one.
Okay?
We're gonna keep an eye out for that sort of thing.
Uh, Pill?
Amazing.
Like, this run is incredible so far.
Uh, right.
Do we find some secrets, or what's the plan here?
I think I know where there is one.
Ah, wait a minute.
This room is, like, narrow.
One of that matters.
I got ten bombs, who cares?
Okay, what about here?
Nice!
Enrichness.
Money equals power, right?
We have that.
Yes, we do.
Even better.
Now, in the shop, was there anything that I wanted?
Real bad?
Not really.
But I guess I can take this.
Let's donate the rest, man.
We have so much, you know?
Donate the rest.
Oh, we broke it.
Damn.
Okay, uh, let's go to the bus.
And get out of here.
I'm scared of accidentally hitting something on the way that damages me.
Oh, this wasn't here.
Here we are.
I'm gonna keep the perfection.
Taking damage destroys the trinket.
That is...
I feel like the wise play here is actually not to keep this.
I think the wise play is to keep the, uh, the cross.
But I'm not wise.
We can afford to be a little bold in our current situation.
Mine's too.
Uh, let's go in here.
So there's just permanently two items all the time for some reason now.
Boom!
More bombs.
Okay, just straight up more bombs.
And let's not forget the credit card.
Uh, many... makes any purchable item and pickups.
Okay, so we gotta find the treasure room or the shop, I mean.
Yeah.
Oh, I didn't even see those guys.
No!
My perfection!
I didn't see them!
That's unfair, man.
Did not see them.
Uh, do you mind waking up there, sir?
Hello.
Oh, I gotta get closer.
What the hell is this?
A lever has opened!
I think.
Something happened just now.
What the heck?
Did you hear that?
Jim.
Okay.
He's almost looked like they're wearing dice on their heads.
A little bit, right?
I don't even need that.
Let's save it.
Also, I'm definitely going a little faster than I should right now, just because I feel so...
brazen, you know?
I should slow down.
There's no rush here.
There's no need to go crazy.
Just because we're at another button.
I heard something on the left!
What is happening here?
Something big has opened.
Okay, dead end.
This room is gonna be scary.
Never mind.
Imagine having perfection and then losing it to a spiky chest.
That would suck.
Okay, so the boss is here.
We can make any item free in there now.
Let's just do it.
Battery pack.
Instant energy.
Oh, okay.
That's kind of bad.
Turi.
26 bombs.
We blow this guy up for sure.
I'm gonna donate the rest.
Oh wait, it's broken.
Fuck.
Never mind.
Uh, so the boss is here.
But I'm not done exploring.
I also want to go inside the curse room.
There's also a blue heart here if we need it later.
Another one of these buttons.
Aha!
So if you couldn't fly, you now have access to this.
All right.
Wait, can I actually...
Whoa!
Wait, what?
Where's my Ludovico?
Excuse me, what happened?
What?
We only have a knife piece.
That's gotta mean there's another knife piece in here.
This is like a sort of challenge now.
You have to sort of let go of your earthly possessions and make it through without the help of your items.
Something like that.
I mean, I still have my items if you look at the right side of the screen.
Creepy music.
Jim.
Imagine we end up fighting a boss by the name of Jim.
I'm scared of him.
There's no enemies.
What the fuck is this?
Not...
oh.
There's an enemy.
I let go of the keyboard for a second there.
We got enemies.
Enemy.
Wait, can you even take damage?
Oh, wait, I gotta use the knife, I think.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
No, wait, what?
Oh, wait, I can... Oh, shit!
I didn't realize I could leave.
Hey, you like bombs?
Fuck on that, bitch.
Uh...
This is weird.
Go, go, go.
Huh?
That sounded like Mom.
Mom is calling.
What is going on in this game?
Wait, I'm dual wielding knives.
Look.
Yeah, don't get close to me, brother.
I'm gonna fuck you, I'm gonna cut you.
Dude, another one of these?
Hell yeah.
Oh, hell yeah.
I think four or five red hearts is a good sweet spot.
What if I take these now?
Okay, that's...
I wish I could get in here.
Dude, I don't know what's happening, so...
We have...
A flashy door!
I'm ready.
I am so fucking ready.
Are you ready?
Um...
There's nothing else I want to do here.
Actually, there is another curse room.
I'm gonna cut our way through.
Uh...
Wait, why am I so lost?
Here we go.
Be good.
Oh, an item!
And bombs.
Curse eye.
Oh, wait, wait, no, no, no, no, no!
Ah, ha, ha, ha, ha!
I don't like that one.
Anything but that one.
Fuck.
Peel me up.
Give me health at least.
Okay, guys, we can't take damage.
This is now the new mandate.
Also, we gotta try to throw that knife at enemies.
Tough twins.
Did it do anything?
Ah, wait, we gotta...
Right.
Oh, that was easy.
Stuy, damage and range up.
Okay, that's good, I guess.
Okay, uh, we go in here now.
Wait, if I go back...
Ahh, now we go grab the hearts.
Heh, heh, heh, heh.
Optimized gameplay.
Don't you look at that.
He's done it again.
The madman.
Yoink, yoink!
Not bad at all, and that's pretty much it, right?
There's no other hearts.
Look at the icon up there with the railroad.
Mines, indeed.
Dep, dep, dep, dep.
Right, nothing in there.
Okay, uh, we're goin'.
Down the hatch.
Mossel, Leon?
I got...
aww.
Okay, fine, I committed.
We're opening this.
Hey, we got another key, that's nice.
It's kind of awkward, though, with the...
throwing this knife when...
when I have the little Vico, you know?
It's... it's weird.
Is the knife actually damage enemies?
Whoa, look at that one!
We're gonna save it.
Actually, there's no need to, because...
we're gonna have buffers on it.
Yeah, that's cool.
Okay, TNT.
Oh!
Jaira?
Ah, you bastard, I didn't even see you there.
Get knifed, son!
Thank you.
That's weird.
Paralysis.
Just do it.
Maybe I'll accidentally walk over it later and pick it up, right?
Now I won't.
It was the smart thing to do.
Also, we can't take damage, because we're gonna get teleported to Narnia.
Oh my god!
Wait, why didn't I get, uh...
Oh, taking damage!
Wait, mid-charge!
Wait a minute!
It doesn't affect me!
Right?
I'm not charging shit!
I'm constantly charged!
Hey, hey!
Not bad!
At least I think that's how that works.
Can enemies use the teleport thing?
Broken remote.
Figures the teleport effect each time an active item is used.
Um...
No!
Absolutely not.
Sounds like a bad idea.
Shop!
Dude, this run is so much fun.
It's insane.
Discovering so much new stuff.
The jar, I don't want that actually.
I don't want any of this.
Maybe that one.
The hermit?
The hermit is to go to the shop, right?
Oh wait, I'm in the shop.
Fuck.
That was so stupid actually.
Didn't even make any sense.
I can't explain that one, okay?
This is not helping the allegations.
The siren with a little musical note.
How you like?
You like knives?
You're dead!
What?
Pageant boy.
Watch this.
Yara.
Money.
Rich!
Probably unnecessary, but you know.
It's fun.
So where do I go now?
There's still a curse room I want to explore.
Oh wait, I think I know where there's a secret.
It's gotta be right here, right?
Fuck!
Here, the assaysal ludovigo combo is goated.
There's nothing else like it.
Trying to steal my battery?
I think not.
Broken magnet.
Pulls coins?
I don't care.
Big chubby.
Familiar that charges slowly?
I don't care.
Give me that.
Politactically, hold me.
What was that?
And I was holding two cards, pills of runes at a time.
Drops one random card, pill of rune on pickup.
AWOS!
I like that one.
This is a floor decoration.
And what
is that?
Free lemonade.
Spawn a large pool of damaging yellow creep that lasts for 19 seconds.
Not 18 or 20, but 19.
Very carefully calibrated by the...
What do you call it?
The balanced department.
I think I may like that.
Compared to the flush.
This one is also four charges.
Nah.
I'm gonna flush enemies.
It also sounds cooler, you know?
To flush enemies.
This could be a secret.
Let me check the other side.
Looking good so far.
Looking very good, in fact.
Dammit!
Fight room is open!
Dobby's head.
Oh, that's actually maybe good for me.
No problem.
Broken padlock.
That is actually good for me.
Because I am lacking keys.
Spawns two to four.
Let's take that one.
Instead of flushing.
I'm happy.
More pills.
Another health up.
Yeah.
Speed down is not that great.
But what can you do?
Okay.
Get the hell out of here.
And then just all the way left.
Wait, wait, wait.
Actually.
Let's do... Oh, wait.
Oh, no.
I need another charge.
There's battery somewhere, right?
Ah, whatever.
I was gonna say, maybe we can teleport to the secret room.
But whatever.
And we go down.
Okay, so now...
We're just gonna keep taking it slow.
Everything's going wonderful.
The best part is we kill enemies so fast that we can actually save up on these flies.
So when we get to a boss, it's gonna be...
Reckoning.
I don't know if you can save like that, but you know what I mean.
I took damage from something.
Dude, what is happening here?
Library.
There it is.
There it is!
My old pal.
It's good to see you.
That's what we need.
This guy wants keys?
I got it!
I got keys for him.
Yo, thanks!
What else you got for me?
I thought I had 29 keys.
Why does this keep happening?
I am legitimately unable to see the difference between those two.
I always mix them up.
God fucking damn it, man.
I thought I was gonna do like 29 of those right now.
What a weird room.
Also, where the fuck are we?
I just noticed how weird this place is.
Like weird.
Range, we don't care.
Damage, we do care.
Health, we have so much already.
I think maybe it's better to take this.
Technology!
Wait, why did that work with this?
It plays its tears with an...
What?
Whoa, look at that coil!
The coil of death, baby!
Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho!
That looks insane!
Whoo!
Oh, yeah!
I feel great about this.
This is gonna slap, isn't it?
I'm afraid to find out how much damage I'm gonna do.
But it's gonna be good.
Paralysis, I take it!
Paralysis highs my buddy!
Take the minus range, who cares?
Eat them all!
I need to be contained!
I'm too strong.
Okay, calm down.
Don't get ahead of yourself now.
Don't get ahead of yourself.
We're still weak.
The stars.
Ooh, let's do that one.
Okay, so there's no planetarium confirmed.
That was just to check that, you know?
It's fine.
We're gonna hide over here, and just sit back and let the tears do the work.
Just gonna use it.
Now I kinda regret taking so many red hearts since I got this book now.
That's okay.
Maybe a devil deal can come in and save the day for me.
Man, this is looking crazy.
Whoa, the DPS is crazy!
Whoo!
Not bad, huh?
Uh,
let's go left.
God, it feels good to have one of these runs again.
Friends till the end, yeah!
Join my army.
Before I go in there, I need to explore everything.
Haggle us!
Could maybe come in handy.
Okay, so, Champion Belt, definitely buying that.
And I can't see shit because of this thing.
I didn't mean to buy that, that was a mistake.
Turn that one into a black one as well, and then take the battery.
I need keys, what is it with keys?
Okay, donate.
Ah, we're fully donated.
Wow!
What the fuck is this room?
Scary.
And that's pretty much this floor.
Cleansed!
I'm gonna rinse her.
Watch.
I took damage, that's unacceptable.
Unbelievable.
Polaroid, or...
Wait, wait, so, negative.
I think I want... oh, wait, wait.
Take the negative.
Watch this.
Yeah!
What's that?
A crown?
Dark Prince's crown, loss is power?
While at one red heart, the crown activates and gives plus two fire rate.
I gotta get my hearts down then.
If I can.
Like this?
Rotten baby.
Yeah!
I need more devil deals.
Dude, this is sick.
This is absolutely sick.
Like, what is this even?
Mom's heart?
Wait, what the fuck?
Why is this... I am so confused.
Well, I know this fight.
It's a little different.
Well, you're dead.
What do I do?
This one looks sus.
Oh, wait.
There's a fucking door.
I didn't see the door.
Holy shit.
Wait, what is happening here?
The music is all messed up now.
I'm scared.
What the hell?
Rotten heart has appeared in the basement.
Corpse one?
Are we inside a decomposing corpse right now?
Sure looks like it.
I don't know how I feel about that.
Why are there more and more fucking areas in this game?
This game doesn't end!
How does this happen?
Wait, don't go in there yet.
We're gonna wait a bit.
Damn, son.
I don't know what's happening.
Ugh.
There's the other curse room.
Everything dies.
Here's that.
Key is so needed.
Definitely fighting.
Is this poison gonna hurt me?
I'm afraid of moving.
Oh my god.
Okay, that was not worth it at all.
This place is weird.
I'm just gonna hang back here and just do that, yeah.
Clean it up for me.
Thank you.
Dude, the fact that they're taking so long to die and I have so much damage...
Oh, I think this place is difficult.
But I'm getting the easy treatment right now because I have a crazy build, you know?
Look how much HP that guy has, dude!
That is wild!
Holy shit!
Wow.
32 bombs.
We should be looking for secrets after we're done exploring this place.
Okay, you definitely take damage in the green shit, but not immediately.
You can still move through what it seems.
I love this music.
It's so fitting for whatever the hell is going on.
Sick.
Boss here?
Not yet.
Wait, right here.
That was actually bad.
I see why that wouldn't be a secret room.
What the...
Bloodshot eye!
Familiar that blocks enemy shots, deals contact, damage, and fires shots at enemies in its direct line of sight.
Don't mind if I do!
Hand it to the collection.
It's raining blood!
Yeah.
Okay then.
AWAS.
My favorite one.
I'm still scared here.
How am I so good?
I am an error.
Error, error.
Uh oh.
Okay, we're fine.
AWAS.
Wait, what?
Did I kill the guy in the center?
I didn't mean to.
Oh.
Black card triggers the effect of the card held without consuming it.
Does that work for AWAS?
Let me try.
Let's try and do it...
Uh, floor...
That's a...
Is that a floor decorate?
This is a...
That one.
Okay, it could just be because there's no...
I'm not sure.
I'm actually kind of afraid of leaving us behind.
Like, this is so dear to me.
Like, what if...
This door somehow closes later and I can't go back or something?
I don't know, I'm scared.
I need to decide about...
We can't make mistakes like that.
Not in the corpse.
Well, there you go.
Very good.
This is what I like to see.
Take my money.
Just gonna park this laser right on top of him, so if any flies spawn, you know.
And he's off.
Sure, I'll take that.
Didn't really feel like donating to that.
Uh, it's time for the curse rooms.
No, actually, let's go for the boss first.
I feel it.
Kymera!
What the fuck are you?!
Okay.
No problem.
I'm too broken right now.
More tears and spectral tears, I mean, we already have that, so whatever.
And you know what, reduce our red heart, so we need that.
We gotta get to one heart, right?
Then good things happen, according to...
That one.
Wait, I wonder if that means...
You only have one red heart, or it's just your...
HP is one.
Red heart.
Meaning, I could have just used the blood donation machine for this.
I read this as, you gotta have only one red heart.
Like, in your... arsenal.
You know what I mean?
Maybe I'm wrong about that.
Damn.
Um...
Let's just... go.
Go further down!
Corpse two!
We also have hagalas.
Uh, let me just see this again.
All breakable obstacles and turrets.
Kills or removes the armor from many stone enemies.
I see.
I also have the AWAS, uh... strength.
Okay, so here's the plan.
We're gonna find a floor decoration.
None of this screams floor decoration to me at all.
Maybe this, but it's too big, no?
May... uh, no, there's nothing in here.
Wow!
Huge!
Now, uh, the floor has been decorated with the blood of my enemies, so now I can't see what's actually a decoration.
Maybe that one?
Please.
Fuck!
I guess it's just about trial and error until you know what counts as what doesn't.
That was a waste.
I blew hard in here.
Now I'm gonna hide in here.
This is the plan.
Whoa, whoa!
Okay, okay, okay.
Turn the blue one into black.
There's the boss.
Unidentified.
Two of diamonds.
Doubles?
Isaac's coins.
Sure.
That's even more damage.
Wait, I need to explore everything.
Especially with all these blue and black hearts lying around.
Hide in the corner.
Nice.
Tears down.
Dude, this song is really nice.
What a vibe.
I can see myself just listening to the song outside of playing the game, you know?
This is like a mood thing.
Curse room time.
You know what would really slap right now?
A wafer.
That would be amazing.
I mean...
Yeah!
This is how we're gonna get to one heart!
Fuck yeah!
Wait, we gotta get some more energy on this.
Wait, I can do it again!
And now we switch.
Now we're at one heart.
Gimme that.
Strength.
What did that do again?
Health, speed, damage, range.
Okay.
Okay, well you were dead.
You got the curse room.
Oh god.
Is that Bob's curse?
It is.
Plus five bombs, bombs, damage, poison, enemies, and bomb.
Explosions leave behind poison gas.
I think it's immune to poison!
Hey!
This place is filled with that shit.
That's probably really good.
Here.
Yeah!
I can't explain it.
I'm just good at finding secrets now.
I'm just good at it now.
It's like you have a feeling, a sixth sense for it.
Watch me find the other one.
It's gonna be... here.
It was a test.
I knew there wasn't anything there.
I was just confirming that.
Wait, is that...
Oh, is that a hole I jump into in the center?
Oh!
Mother!
What?
Destroy the arms.
What are you... You're gonna knife?
You're gonna knife me?
Why is mom looking like that?
I don't like that.
The fuck is that?
Oh God!
Whoa!
Oh, she's saying Isaac!
Oh God!
Ohoy!
What the fuck?
Dude, what the...
Whoa!
Mom?
Jesus Christ!
Fuckin' hell!
Fuck you, Mom!
Dear Mom.
You suck!
What are you drawing?
Isaac, let me see it.
Give it to me now.
This is what you think of me?
This is what I am to you?
A monster?
No one does.
After all I've done for you, this is how you view me.
You think I'm a monster, Isaac?
I'll show you a monster!
What the hell?
I can't even look at you.
There better be a fucking ending to this game where everything is good.
I can't stand looking at Isaac suffering like that, man.
That is horrible.
Jesus Christ.
Especially, I'm just thinking, this happens to some kids out there, you know?
It makes it even worse.
It's not just fiction, right?
Oh my gosh.
I don't know, no.
Devil's Crown has appeared.
You unlocked Jacob and Esau.
You unlocked... I think something...
What about Challenge 8?
Strange door!
Dude!
Strange door, baby!
I'm gonna get to that strange door!
That is awesome!
Oh my god, man, that cutscene cut deep.
That was crazy.
Isaac, you...
Jacob and Esau.
Wait a minute, okay, theory time.
Remember the cutscene where someone put up a poster for Isaac missing?
Because obviously, she locked us in the chest, right?
And she left us there to die, the skeleton.
That's how we died.
We drew the picture, she threw us in the fucking chest, and we just died in there, man.
And I think, because all these characters are versions of myself, this is the only one so far that has two names on it.
I think that Jacob was my friend in real life, in the game, right?
And Esau kind of sounds like Isaac.
Right, so maybe it's Isaac and Jacob forever, like the friends.
I know I'm pulling stuff out of my ass here, kind of, but...
Basically what I'm saying is, I...
Fuck, I hate that he died in the chest like that.
So, so...
Fuck you, mom, like...
Fuck you, mom.
I can't handle it.
I gotta try this.
So wait, three hearts plus one, speed two, one damage plus three.
How the... Wait, hold on a minute.
I gotta just take a look at this.
What?
Look at the stats!
Oh, look, there's HP in the bottom right as well.
Does that mean if one of us dies, it's over, or...
Is it like, leave no man behind?
What the hell?
Dude, I kind of don't want to play right now, because I got so...
Oh, no.
Oh, that's fucked up, man.
Oh, that complicates things.
Shit.
This is basically like Yulith.
What is this character?
Dude, if this actually ends up being, like, a really good character, characters...
The perfect title for the VOD would be, my new favorite characters.
Collector transforms the current character into another character, chosen at random.
Activating has a 50% chance to remove them.
How the fuck does that work?
Oh, wait!
One of them hasn't...
What's up, Mike dude?
What's going on, friend?
This is... I don't know what's happening.
We have a lot of HP, which is amazing.
That's kind of a funny item to find, isn't it?
Like, on a character with two characters.
I thought we were going to have two different characters from that.
So, wait, do we have any items or something?
No, not really.
Wait, we don't even have a fucking...
Oh, we don't have the void thingy.
Not my Apollyon, that's all I'm saying.
This is the dollar store version.
3.5 damage is good, though.
The best thing, though, is all the HP I have.
You know what that means, right?
We're going to make deals with the devil!
And we're going to get Brimstone.
Sniper.
Man, that run was crazy, though.
Like, so much shit happened, new areas, new bosses.
Weird secrets discovered, and it all ended with a beautiful kill on Mother.
I mean...
I'm still reeling from that, I can't lie.
Like, that was phenomenal.
That felt so good in my tummy.
And then the sad cutscene happened, and I felt a little less good.
It's like the earlier cutscenes that showed him being in the box was like, okay, sure.
It's sad, but it wasn't like real, you know?
I feel like now that became real.
It really made it a lot worse now.
Dammit.
Alright, one bomb, we could maybe look for a secret.
Could be right here, actually.
Let me see the other side.
Yeah, why not, let's try.
Fuck.
Dingle, oh, I wish I could swoop you up in my arms and throw you down the toilet.
I forgot the word for the plunger thingy.
Oh!
Why is Dingle all red?
You can't get to me.
I have poop as protection.
Oh, you know what the red poop is?
That is the type of poop the day after you've eaten spicy food.
That's what that is supposed to mean, I think.
It stings, you know, it burns.
It just occurred to me.
You don't want to charge me?
Advanced strategies here.
Yeah, you suck.
Flawless, flawless.
Dinner, why not?
Added to the pool of HP.
Man, demon deals are going to go hard.
That's all I'm saying.
Downpour one.
100% demon.
You know what the strategy is, actually?
You beeline it for the boss.
Before you start losing the demon chance, right?
That is the optimal way to do it.
Hey, dude, what's up?
Oh, there's more, there's more.
I barely didn't see them, but I saw them.
Uh, this way.
I got a key.
A chance to fire a slowing shot increases with luck.
What's that?
Yo, massive damage.
Holy shit.
That's crazy.
I'm one-shotting these fools.
Not bad at all.
Oh, god.
This is a great start.
Like, it doesn't get better than this.
Oh, I have no map.
At button.
Three buttons.
I got a prism.
One gem.
Oh, okay.
Minimin.
Oh, not these guys.
Oh, wow.
Just
keep moving.
Honestly, that's the strategy.
Stay on the move.
I'm gonna move the other way now.
I'm gonna get a little more in the center.
I actually don't like going right side round.
I'm gonna go clockwise.
Oh.
Dude.
I'm starting to believe.
I can feel it.
I'm the one!
It's me!
I'm the chosen one!
Holy shit!
Yep.
Grab it, whatever it is.
I don't care.
Kinda sad that we didn't have two items in here.
It is what it is.
Well, this floor was not done yet.
Gotta keep going.
Is that a viable?
It is.
Oh, my goodness.
I'm not used to seeing this item and actually being able to read the description of it.
Every time I see this, there's no description on it.
It's the first time.
Well, I don't have money for any of this.
Rip.
Maybe I'll find some money.
Excuse me.
This way?
No.
This is where I spawned, I think.
We could give him some money.
Or blow him up.
Pride.
Wasn't much of a foe.
Could go in there.
I think it wouldn't make sense to do that now because we at 0% demon anyway, so fuck it.
You know what, I think the optimal strategy there is to push a bomb into the center.
If you can somehow do that from the angle.
And then hit all four at the same time.
Let's blow this guy up.
Nothing down there.
Nothing up here right now.
Dead end.
Wait, was it this one and left?
Oh yeah.
Let's go.
Maybe I'll try to go fast.
I mean, we have the health, we have the damage.
Speed runtime.
I wanna fight.
Whoosh.
What the hell is that?
Treasure rooms will always contain...
Okay.
Well, we're gonna save the money for the treasure room then.
Dude, that's actually a crazy item.
If you just have 10 gold like I have, you can already re-roll a bunch I guess.
Maybe two or three times.
Solid.
Okay.
Ex-lax.
Boss, I mean, we can speed.
Wormwood.
He's doing that now.
What did I get hit by?
Man, that just took my 9% chance out the window.
I got two bombs for this.
Speed.
It's time for whoosh.
Get away from me.
Maximum speed.
Is
this the guy that does bzzzt?
No, it's not.
It's gonna get messy.
No problem.
Gotta be much faster though.
What the hell?
Lazy worm.
Damage, uh, shot speed.
Uh, nah.
Not feeling it.
What?!
Faster.
The boss is here!
Dude, speed.
Speed is real.
No!
Go!
Great Gideon.
The all flowing.
Something about waves here.
Yeah, one of six.
Oh, these guys are so annoying.
Oi!
That was kind of lucky.
Good.
What's happening?
Oh, right, he's doing that.
Nice!
Okay, not bad.
Dude, so much HP.
Can we stop with the HP at this point?
More damage, perhaps.
Oh well.
Speed run.
We are ahead of the timer.
Uh...
Wait.
Fuck!
Piss!
Ah!
Uh, fine.
Whatever.
I didn't want it anyway.
I have no bombs, dude.
I have a bomb.
Yeah.
Okay, uh, we can't stay here forever.
Speed run.
What is this room?
Nah.
I'm taking so much damage for no reason.
Why you taught me like this?
Uh...
Okay, we take the unknown one.
Like Krifargy.
Like Krifagy?
Tears slow down and hover as they travel.
And tears that touch other tears combine, increasing in size and damage.
Tears that stop completely or hit an obstacle burst into a ring of eight smaller tears.
Whoa.
That sounds...
Oh, so if you run with it...
Good things happen.
Kinda cool.
Uh, there's a room here where I want to explore.
13 coins.
We can make it.
Coupon.
Yo.
Uh, fine.
I'll take this instead.
And a healing.
Let's go.
Just because I'm not sure how much HP I have.
Okay.
Boss is here.
Nice.
Go!
Hornfell.
Wow.
Dude, calm down.
Calm down.
Holy shit, man.
More tears.
I like it.
Wait, do I have HP to do this?
Uh, dude, I'm too scared.
I'm going down here.
I may actually die if I go through that door.
Let's see how much HP I actually have.
Oh, I could have done it.
Fuck, wait.
Is that a strange door?
There's a white rectangle on it.
Or a trapezoid.
It looks like a strange door to me.
Nice treasure room.
Oh, wait, there's invisible.
We can re-roll.
Big chubby... I don't like it.
Re-roll.
One soul heart.
Yes.
That is the ultra poor man's wafer.
I need some shot speed.
This is getting ridiculous.
Tongue people!
Let me in here.
What do we got?
Pill?
I don't like any of it.
Go.
I really love this effect because you can just put down mines like that that explode after a while.
And it's a lot of DPS.
Boss is here.
It's going very well.
Oh, God.
Dude, come on.
How do you dodge that?
Mom.
It's Mom.
You're dead, Mom.
Look what I got for you.
I should just keep shooting.
It's like I said, it's going to spread out into little flowers of damage, you know?
Mom is really angry, it seems.
She just wants to stop me.
Dude, are you kidding?
No way, dude.
You.
Focus.
Hold on a minute.
I need to... I need just a second.
Oh, man.
Okay, so hold on.
1.98 damage.
Can we use to open a string?
Wait a minute.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Also, where's the... I guess I wasn't fast enough.
Oh, shit.
Well, RIP.
Not that I would have won anyway at this point.
I mean, with 1 HP, come on.
We have a problem here because I can't get back out.
I think you need some kind of teleport.
Can I get back out?
Let me out.
Like, that door... has gotta be it, right?
It has to be it.
And that would make a beautiful secret as well, right?
Having to teleport out of the room?
I can see it.
I see it clear as day.
Okay, we gotta focus on HP, exactly.
Good.
More HP.
Full healing now.
No mistakes.
Whoa!
That was scary.
Not the holes.
Nice.
Just keep giving me healing.
Do I use the other key here?
I don't think I do, actually.
Too valuable.
Dude, thank you for the healing!
That's crazy.
That's exactly what I needed.
Ah-ha!
Broken remote!
Could be interesting.
Question is, can I make this happen?
Wait, wait, wait.
Let me see.
If I...
No, it's not enough.
I thought I could maybe destroy that thing in the center and it would make a bridge, but wait.
It's too far away to make a bridge anyway, so whatever.
Why am I getting so much healing?
Isn't this kind of unheard of?
Wow, did you see that dodge?
That was crazy.
More healing.
I mean, maybe we can still make it for Hush.
Because we found the boss so fast here.
Let's give it a shot.
Oh, God.
Get away from me.
Oh, that's nice.
Keep jumping down the holes, Isaac.
Gotta go faster.
Oh, I'm taking this, though.
Ah!
I knew that was gonna happen, man.
I saw it right when I was...
I need a key.
Unlucky.
Jackie, what is it?
Jackie is at my feet again.
I guess it is food time in half an hour for her, so...
She's getting ready, you know?
Ready to consume.
We have full health.
Damn.
Things are going smoothly here.
Wait, do we have Curse of the Confusion thing?
Because I'm confused.
It's always those guys.
When you don't know what it is, it's these guys.
I'm relying on the flowers that come out to kill them.
It's a cool strategy, actually.
Look, isn't that cool?
Love the flowers.
Oh, Jackie, you cannot be up here.
Soon you shall receive food.
How did I do that without taking damage?
I'm actually insane.
Oh, this room's gonna kill me.
I'm so... Actually, just make a bunch of flowers.
Good luck, good luck.
Make giant flowers as well.
Oh my god, what the frick?
I gotta go get some more healing.
Not looking too good right now.
There we go, that will do.
Boss?
Good, go!
It lives!
No, it doesn't!
How do you hit me when I'm in full mode, full speed?
Okay, time to focus.
Rely on flowers!
Trust in the flowers.
Nice!
Smelter has appeared.
Alright, oh, here we go!
Fuck yeah!
Let's go!
Time for the whoosh!
I don't have a lot of HP though, so this is not great.
Also, this boss, it's kinda hard to deal with when you don't have range, and I don't have range.
But maybe the flowers can help me.
Bot petty!
Heal me!
Heal me up!
Can I please destroy poop spawner blue?
I mean, I don't even know, all these items suck!
Tor stop, I don't want that shit!
Treasure rooms, I mean, okay!
Treasure rooms, right?
Liar!
There's no restock machine!
What is that?
Compass?
The deed?
And an apple.
Pig worms.
Or bird's eye.
Chance when firing tears to also fire a sliding red flame projectile, which deals heavy contact damage to enemies.
Chance increases with luck.
I think I'll take this.
I just want to see what it is.
Teleports Isaac to the treasure room, secret room, super secret room, or error room?
Alrighty.
Libra!
Not a bomb, speed, less tears, less damage.
Is that upgrades or balance?
No, you know what?
I don't like that.
That could maybe come in handy, but that's only going to be used once, right?
Aw, man, I don't know about this.
I don't think I want any of this, actually.
Both of those are bad for me.
Straight up!
Jackie, no!
Please!
I really should just close the door when I play.
I think I'm going to take this.
I think I'm going to take this, because it's a full health.
Damn!
That's good!
Some healing.
Poke go, I can't afford it.
Buy the bomb.
Honestly, donate the rest.
Two coins is still something.
Fuck penny.
Four stop, I think.
I mean...
I guess this one is technically the best one I have.
I think I'm dead.
But let's give it a shot, eh?
The flowers are going to be carrying me here.
Pressure.
Dude, what?
Whoa, that was a bad way to dodge that.
I'm also dodging my own, because I can't tell which ones are his.
Which ones are mine?
Ah, I'm dodging my own projectiles!
Oh
my god.
I think I'm so dead, I'm so dead.
I interlock in here.
Nice music.
I'm really feeling it.
Play from the heart.
I'm modest.
The fuck is that?
Dodge it.
I'm just going to turn into a son of a gun in a second here, and I'm going to have a bad time.
Come on,
flowers.
Make it happen.
Oh, not this crap.
Yeah.
And then a fucking fly hits me.
Gotta be kidding me.
Stops for you.
Not that way.
Whoa!
That was a good run though.
That was nice.
Actually okay.
I don't mind.
Let's call it there.
That was actually amazing.
What?
This is some good runs.
Hold on.
I'm going to turn that down.
And turn this up.
It's fitting as hell.
Oh yeah.
What do you say to that, guys?
Did we win today or what?
Crazy dodging at the end, right?
Sometimes you're in a flow state and you're just like...
working out.
Killed mom again for like the fifth time in her fifth form or whatever.
I'm sure there's going to be more forms.
There's got to be a final form.
I love the complete 180 of you being set at the ending and then a strange door.
Yeah.
I'm glad it happened.
Because I was really down bad with the sadness, you know?
But then all of a sudden, I was down with the sickness.
A strange door, baby.
And boy did we find a strange door.
I haven't seen this door more strange than that.
44,857,475 forms.
You're lying.
That's not true.
Thank you for the Lazarus appreciation last week.
Lazarus is a cool guy, man.
He is an all around good character.
Solid HP, solid damage.
He's not like shitty in any ways.
He fucking comes back when he dies.
I mean, you got to love him.
Watch this music.
It is...
One of the most epic tracks in a video game sequence.
I'm not going to reveal what happens, of course, in that sequence, but...
Just play Ore.
It's a great game.
What do those scribbles on the screen mean?
I don't know.
Ask Edmond Macmillan.
He's the one who wrote them.
I wrote him a message and was like, Dude, I'm going to stream your game.
Do you mind making a background for me?
And he did.
He wrote this down for me.
I'm lying about that, by the way.
That's not true.
I don't have that kind of clout.
You unlocked and found so many things to stream.
I never played Isaac before, so it's fun unlocking things with you.
Hey, that's cool.
What do you think of the game so far, Gemini?
Or Gimini?
Or someone who hasn't played it before, but just watched me play it.
Is it confusing?
Do you understand what's happening on the screen, or...
Are you just going with the flow?
So did you like Jacob and Esau?
Yeah, I did.
He turned into my favorite character.
It's kind of funny that the boss title from yesterday was...
This is my new favorite character, which is, of course, the Apollyon character, right?
And then today I get a character where I turn into him.
So the title's going to be...
This is my new favorite characters.
Or these are.
It's just the same character.
Or this is still my favorite characters.
I love that.
That's the best title, right?
Isn't it?
I feel like that's...
Sometimes you just have the perfect title in mind.
If you want that Apollyon run, you would have made some people very rich.
Since everyone voted you would lose with Jacob and Esau.
Oh, that's funny.
That is actually hilarious.
Is this my first loss to Hush, by the way?
I feel like I've been slapping that guy left and right.
But now, finally, it was my time to get slapped.
Amazing.
I don't think I've ever lost to... No, that's not true.
I was about to say Delirium, but I have lost to that guy.
It is the Hush one that I have been doing well against.
It was so pock when you figured out the mirror.
It will be even more pock next to figure out whatever.
Dude, I feel so stupid in hindsight because...
Obviously there was something with that mirror, right?
Because it was on the map and it was very...
It was on every single time I was there, the mirror was there.
I should have just asked myself the question, what can I actually do on this floor, you know?
And obviously the fire was one of the things that are different.
So I should have realized that earlier.
But I'm glad I figured it out.
Minus seven luck must be... I mean, I thought for sure it was a trade-off, you know?
That was an interaction, a genuine interaction.
You blow up the mirror and something happens.
The game responds by showing you a destroyed mirror.
Minus seven luck?
Surely that could have been something there.
Like a trade-off, right?
A trade-off that I didn't know what was.
Oliver, didn't you know ghosts can travel through mirrors in real life?
I did not know that.
I don't believe in ghosts.
So therefore my eyes aren't real.
Dude, Jaden Smith would love downpour.
Am I right?
The mother ending cutscene was so sad.
Dude, I was actually crying a little bit.
I was shedding a manly tear.
Who am I kidding?
I shed a normal tear.
That was sad as hell.
I think so, Giminy.
I think it's the first time we heard his voice.
I was about to comment on it, but then I got absorbed in the cutscene.
I was like taking it back when I heard his voice.
I was like, what?
You know?
Do you believe in mirrors?
I don't.
They don't really show reality.
It's fake.
Should we watch the starting cutscene?
I should actually.
That's a good point.
Okay, I gotta go.
Jackie is murdering me for food.
Even though it's technically in 15 minutes, she needs to be fed.
Guys, I'm gonna go to my parents tomorrow and be there for a couple days.
So no streams for the next couple days.
After that, we're back to Isaac.
I'm gonna try and keep the excitement contained within me.
So yeah, my father has a birthday.
So we gotta go celebrate that.
Thanks for watching everyone, and I'll see you around!
Enjoy your day.
Next time we will win even more.
Bye-bye.